MARGARET HEAVEY

WEB DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I have spent the last 8 years of my career refining my analytical, technical, problem solving and leadership skills in the BioPharmaceutical and Medical Device Industry. My passion for learning new skills and continuous improvement has driven me to explore new opportunities and develop the Software Development skills I have learned.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior QC Analyst (Technical Resources) I Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Limerick | December 2023 - Present

- Subject Matter Expert for Commercial Product Method Performance
- I was responsible for data trending of product performance, maintaining up-to-date product testing databases, writing periodic technical reports and ensuring compliance.
- I contributed significantly to developmental projects for process improvement and automation.

Key Skills: data analysis, technical writing, data trending and review, problem solving and project and time management

QC Analyst (Technical Resources) | Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Limerick | October 2022 - Dec 2023

- Data trending of product performance, maintaining up-to-date product testing databases, writing periodic technical reports and ensuring compliance.
- I was responsible for managing transfer and validation projects, ensuring periodic targets were met and input from all relevant stakeholders was addressed appropriately.

Key Skills: data analysis, technical writing, data trending and review, problem solving and project and time management

Lead QC Analyst | Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Limerick | June 2018 - October 2022

- As a Team Lead I provided support and guidance to employees and coordinated workload scheduling and lead monthly performance reviews with direct reports
- I was responsible for the technical writing and review of SOPs, protocols, reports, laboratory investigations as well as data review
- I performed sample and reagent preparation and distribution to support laboratory testing.
- I was responsible for maintaining laboratory reagents, equipment and supplies and the coordination and scheduling of periodic equipment calibrations.

Key Skills: teamwork, technical writing, problem solving, project and time management and laboratory analytical techniques.

QC Microbiology Team Lead Complete Laboratory Solutions (CLS), Galway | December 2016 - June 2018

- I provided support and guidance to employees and coordinated workload scheduling and lead monthly performance reviews with direct reports
- I was responsible for the technical writing and review of SOPs, protocols, reports, laboratory investigations as well as data review
- I was responsible for conducting Validations and Method Developments.

- I was responsible for coordinating and leading Internal and External Proficiency Schemes
- I liased with clients and acted as a main point of contact within the microbiology laboratory. Key Skills: teamwork, technical writing, problem solving, project and time management and laboratory analytical techniques.

QC Microbiologist Complete Laboratory Solutions (CLS), Galway | May 2016 - December 2016

• I carried out microbial growth promotion and testing of client samples as per USP, EP, ISO17025 and other relevant ISO Standards.

Key Skills: teamwork, problem solving, time management and laboratory analytical techniques.

EDUCATION

Higher Diploma in Software Development (NFQ level 8) I Galway Mayo Institute of Technology, Galway | 2019-2022

Postgraduate Diploma in Applied Microbiology (NFQ level 9) | National University of Ireland, Galway | 2015-2016

Master of Science in Ecological Assessment (NFQ level 9) | University College Cork | 2010-2011 | Bachelor of Science in Microbiology (NFQ level 8) | National University of Ireland, Galway | 2004-2009